# STEPHANOS HADJIMYLOS

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+357 99251437
+1 5714207244
stephanoshadjimylos@gmail.com
personal website
linkedin
github
SKILLS
Time Management
Communication
Project Management
Soft Skills
Fast Learner
Critical & Analytical Thinking
EDUCATION
Master's Electrical & Electronics Engineering
University of Sussex
2014-2018
LANGUAGES
English —
Greek

CONTACT

#### ABOUT ME

Software Developer with several years of experience in Back End Development, specializing in Python. Experience working on innovative projects from the design phase to deployment. Skilled team member that knows how to translate business requirements to technical requirements with excellent time management and communication skills. I am a hard worker and fast learner with experience in high profile multi-cultural companies, always looking to better myself and my abilities. I have both EU & US citizenship and am willing to travel for work

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Software Engineer - Backend**

Warply 2022-Current

- Responsible for design, development and testing of new features.
- Involved in Project Management task delegation.
- Involved in translating business requirements to technical requirements.
- Responsible for communicating with clients to consult on business/technical requirements.
- · Developed and deployed features reaching millions of consumers.

# **Software Engineer - Backend**

Remote 2021-2022

- · Worked on complex custom cyber security analytics product.
- · Worked on complex APIs working in the main Back End of the product.
- Trusted to handle projects & tasks independently, including new features and improving efficiency of legacy code
- Included in the entire cycle of each feature release; Including design, development, bug fixing and deployment
- Excellent communication with QA team for test designs and bug fixing.
- 100% project / feature ownership

#### **Software Engineer - Backend**

Emtech Space P.C

2019-2021

- Worked on a custom SCADA system built in Python from scratch collecting and displaying significant data from all around Greece's electrical grid network.
- Worked on and maintained a custom DSS platform designed to build & deploy applications with minimal code required.
- Worked on complex electrical grid research projects such as integrating prediction algorithms into a SCADA system and a smart scheduling system for Renewable energy resources.
- 100% project ownership.
- Worked on Independent Software Verification & Validation projects for space simulations containing automated unit testing, V&V testing, static analysis.
- Solely created a custom unit test platform for the company's custom DSS platform to enhance test driven development in the company.
- Gained experience in Project Management, over viewing tasks on Jira.
- Was in charge of training & onboarding new members of the team.

# STEPHANOS HADJIMYLOS

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Git
- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- SQLite
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Jira
- FastAPI
- FLASK
- ORMs
- APIs
- Testing
- Jira
- Sonarqube
- Jenkins
- Docker
- Agile Methodology

\_\_\_\_\_

### REFERENCES

#### Vaggelis Alifragkis

+30 694 668 3613

## Stanislav Ermizidis

+30 697 737 8713

ermizidis.stan@gmail.com

### Michael Berketis

+30 698 111 3902

mberketis@gmail.com

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Layer 1 Support Engineer**

Digea

2018-2019

- Layer 1 support for 98% of Greece's television signal.
- Gained experience in specialized antennas, GPS systems, UPS systems, setting up backups for server rooms
- Took on personal projects such as selecting new servers for the company, designing and implementing multi-viewer testing equipment, managing the design and replacement of all the IT equipment used by the NOC team.

## **Network Test Engineer - Internship**

Vodafone (Former Arqiva Wi-Fi)

2016

- Worked on custom Wi-Fi solution for high profile customers such as Heathrow Airport, Holiday Inn, Pret A Manger, etc.
- Responsible for testing the product and reporting bugs to the development team.
- Tested user flow, penetration testing and custom automation tests written.

### **PROJECTS**

## **SCADA System**

Created system for live realtime monitoring of electrical regulatory devices all over Greece.

# **Smart Scheduling System**

Created a system that recommends a smart schedule for renewable energy sources. The schedule is based on predictions algorithms.

## **Space Software Testing**

Worked on ISVV (Independent Software Verification & Validation for small satellites that were going to be launched into space.

## **Loyalty Systems**

Created feature that sends automated messages to consumers that fit specific criteria in order to boost customer interaction.